Guide to the John Gamble Kirkwood Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
John Gamble Kirkwood papers
1947-1961
MS 642
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
9
Correspondence, lectures, and printed material compiled by John Gamble Kirkwood during his tenure at Yale University. The lectures are on statistical mechanics and thermodynamics. Half of the papers are made up of offprints of articles in chemistry by others.
Kirkwood, John G., 1907-1959
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Chemistry Department, Yale University, 1972.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
John Gamble Kirkwood: chemist; student at the California Institute of Technology, 1923-1925; S.B., University of Chicago, 1926; Ph.D., M.I.T., 1929; research fellow, Harvard, 1929-1930; international research fellow, Leipzig and Munich, 1931-1932; research associate, M.I.T., 1930-1931, 1932-1934; assistant professor of chemistry, Cornell, 1934-1937; associate professor, University of Chicago, 1937-1938; Todd professor of chemistry, Cornell, 1938-1947; Sterling professor of Chemistry, Yale, 1956-1959.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, lectures, and printed material compiled by John Gamble Kirkwood during his tenure at Yale University. The lectures are on statistical mechanics and thermodynamics. Half of the papers are made up of offprints of articles in chemistry by others.
Science; Statistical mechanics; Thermodynamics; Chemists; Educators; Kirkwood, John G., 1907-1959; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Department of Chemistry
- Inventory
  - Correspondence
    - A-C, 1951-1961 (Box 1)
    - D-N, 1951-1961 (Box 2)
    - O-Z, 1951-1961 (Box 3)
  - Kirkwood, John G. lectures
    - Selected Topics in Statistical Mechanics (2 vols.), 1947 (Box 3)
    - Thermodynamics (2 vols.), 1947-1961 (Box 3)
    - Thermodynamics (9 vols.), 1947-1961 (Box 4)
  - Printed Material (Box 4)
    - A-F, undated (Box 5)
    - G-K, undated (Box 6)
    - K-M, undated (Box 7)
    - N-R, undated (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous, unsorted, undated (Box 9)